Hello everyone and welcome to
English Pod, my name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we
have an elementary level lesson for you.
This is about fixing things.
That's right so
sometimes in our office or
in our house some small
things may break like
maybe the door or the
air conditioning so in
this case we need to call a
special guy to come and fix it.
So let's listen to today's
dialogue and we'll
be back in a moment to
talk about who this guy is.
The air conditioning is not working.
We need to call a heading
man before we start to fry in here.
Dan is on top of that.
I think they are also
getting the handyman to
fix the bathroom toilet
that keeps clogging up.
That would be convenient.
They might as well ask him
to fix the electrical wiring.
The circuit breakers keep
going out all the time.
It's really annoying.
Yeah you're right.
This office is falling apart.
Frank told me the other
day that the gudders
outside were clogs and that's
why the parking lot was flooded.
I know.
I was in ankle deep water
trying to get to my car that day.
The handyman definitely
has his work cut out for him.
All right we're back so
now let's take a look at some
of those keywords and
phrases on language takeaway.
Our first word today
is the name of this job.
The person is called a handyman.
Okay so that's a profession.
You are a handyman.
Now what exactly does a handyman do?
Well a handyman fixes things.
He is usually a generalist.
He fixes things all over the house,
not just the bathroom or the kitchen.
So he can just fix things
that are a little bit broken.
But if for example
your car is, it needs a
new radiator or it needs
a new important part.
Maybe you would take the car to
someone who is more experienced with cars.
But in the case of a handyman if
anything is broken he can generally fix it.
Okay so as Catherine explained basically a
handyman just does any type or many types
of general work of things that may be
broken around the house or the office.
We had a couple
examples of these in today's
dialogue didn't we what was
that first one kind of gross?
Yeah well he had to
fix the air conditioning
but then he also had to fix the bathroom
toilet because it kept clogging up.
Okay so a toilet gets
clogged up to clog up.
What does this mean?
So it means that something is blocking
the way of the water being able to go out.
So the water doesn't go down.
And sometimes if the
toilet is really clogged
then someone tries
to flush the toilet again
the water comes onto the floor
and it's very dirty and very gross.
That's right so actually maybe
sometimes in the kitchen pieces
of food may fall into the sink
and it may clog up the sink.
Okay so to clog up means to
block or to get in the way of.
That's right.
And apart from the toilets
being clogged up he also
may have to take a look
at the circuit breakers.
Alright so this is not about
water or about plumbing.
Circuit breakers have
to do with electricity
and in this case that
box in your apartment
or near your apartment that
controls the different circuits.
So sometimes if the lights go out, you know
that you have to check the circuit breaker
and make sure that the
circuits are all working properly.
That's right so the
circuit breakers are kind
of like a protection from too much
electricity and that's why they go out.
And now for our final
word on language takeaway.
Something that also got clogged up at their
office we're talking about the gutters.
Alright so many people's
houses have gutters
or sometimes an office
building will have gutters.
These are a trays on
the roof of a house or
a building that will catch
the water when it rains.
So sometimes rain
water can be very very
heavy and it's dangerous on the roof of
your house because it can hurt the roof.
But if it comes into
this gutter into this little
tray then it will come
down and fall on the ground.
So these are a way to protect your roof.
But these often get clogged
up with leaves and with garbage.
That's right.
So they're like small little waves or
little roads if you want to call them.
What are the water can go and
escape and go into a specific place.
We have them on the sides
of roads as well many times.
So gutters that you find
on the ground sometimes
you find them on the roof of a
house but those are a little bit different.
The gutters on the ground
are basically pathways
for water to come
down because if there's
no gutter then all of the water is on
the road and it can flood very quickly.
That's right.
It's a way for the water
and even the garbage
to go on the side of the road
and not be in the way of the cars.
That's right.
You see them on highways
and roads very often
because you don't
want the road filled with
water so these gutters
are a small path where
all the water will fall into it and
escape safely from the highway.
That's right.
All right.
So that's all the time we
have for language takeaway.
Why don't we go back
and have another listen
to the dialogue and we'll be
back soon with Fluency Builder.
The air conditioning is not working.
We need to call a heading
man before we start to fry in here.
Dan is on top of that.
I think they are also
getting the handyman to
fix the bathroom toilet
that keeps clogging
up.
That would be convenient.
They might as well ask him
to fix the electrical wiring.
The circuit breakers keep
going out all the time.
It's really annoying.
Yeah, you're right.
This office is falling apart.
I think told me the
other day that the gutters
outside were clogged and that's
why the parking lot was flooded.
I know.
I was in ankle deep water
trying to get to my car that day.
The handyman definitely
has his work cut out for him.
Now let's take a look at three
key phrases on Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder.
Well, this first phrase is a phrase that
I like to use and I do use it very often.
We heard that Dan is
on top of that, all right?
So we need to call a handyman in here
and he says, nope, Dan is on top of that.
So to be on top of
something, what does it mean?
Well, when she says
Dan is on top of that,
she's basically saying
Dan is taking care of
this or Dan is already calling
the handyman to come and fix it.
So you are aware of the problem
and you're trying to solve it.
Okay, so don't worry, you
don't have to call the handyman.
Dan is on top of that, Dan will call him.
Right.
So to be on top of something is to
make sure that something is done.
So you could say, you know,
Marco, I really, I hope you
stay on top of that project
because it's very important.
Right.
Or don't worry, the report
will be finished on time.
I am on top of that.
Great.
All right, now moving
on to our next phrase,
they were talking about
all the problems that
this office has and the
person said, well, they might as
well ask the handyman to
also fix the electrical wiring.
Okay, so this phrase
might as well is, it's
kind of hard to understand,
I think, sometimes.
Basically what the
speaker is saying is that
while he is doing this, he
can also do something else.
Okay, so he's here,
he can fix many things,
he might as well also
fix electrical wiring.
Right.
So taking advantage
of the fact that you are
already doing something
or you are already
here, you can start doing
something else as well.
Or maybe we could
say this in a different
context to like, you
know, we're going to order
a pizza for lunch,
you know what, Marco,
might as well order two because
there are so many people here.
Right.
So taking advantage
of the fact that we are
ordering pizza, we might as
well get more for everyone.
Okay, and for our last phrase, when they
mentioned all the work that has to be done,
they said the handyman definitely
has his work cut out for him.
Okay, so if someone
has his work cut out for
him, it means that he
has a lot of work to do.
That's right.
You can also say this to
someone that you're talking to.
So Marco, Marco is
writing a book and I say,
hey Marco, that's a
really long book you're
writing, it looks like you really
have your work cut out for you.
That's right.
Or maybe this project is really
difficult, I really have my work cut out.
Okay, so you're basically saying I
have a very hard time ahead of me.
Okay, so that's all the
phrases we have for
you, why don't we have a listen
to our dialogue one last time.
The air conditioning is not working.
We need to call a handyman
before we start to fry in here.
Dan is on top of that.
I think they are also
getting the handyman to
fix the bathroom toilet
that keeps clogging up.
That would be convenient.
They might as well ask him
to fix the electrical wiring.
The circuit breakers keep
going out all the time.
It's really annoying.
Yeah, you're right.
This office is falling apart.
Frank told me the
other day that the gutters
outside were clogged and that's
why the parking lot was flooded.
I know.
I was in ankle deep water
trying to get to my car that day.
The handyman definitely
has his work cut out for him.
So a handyman is also commonly
referred to as a jack of all trades.
That's right.
These are both kind of funny words.
First of all, handy as an adjective
means useful and we're helpful.
Maybe a hammer is a handy tool.
It's a very handy tool or I find my
iPhone has some very handy applications.
I can use the dictionary.
Handyman is someone who's helpful.
He can do many things.
The jack of all trades
is very special because
he is a person that
can do basically any job.
Right.
So sometimes in offices,
people may have someone
that they may refer to
as a jack of all trades.
So he may fix the computers.
He also knows a little
bit about marketing
and there's many odd and
random things around the office.
That's right.
He could say my friend
Paul, he is a jack of all trades.
He can fix a car.
He can cook.
He can fix a door or a
window, but he can also sew.
So he's a jack of all trades.
He has many, many skills.
That's right.
And talking about these
skills, being a handyman
is not a profession per
se, it's actually a trade.
That's right.
And so we say this
because it's something
that you normally do
with your hands and you
don't have to go to
university to study at you and
maybe have an apprenticeship
where you study by working.
And it's one of a few
very, very important
trades like being a
plumber or an electrician,
but a handyman is more general like
we said, you can do many different things.
That's right.
So very interesting.
There are many trades out there.
Maybe you can come on the site and
mention some of these that you may know.
Like for example, a
very well-known trade is
a cobbler, a person
that makes shoes, right?
It's a very weird word
though because shoes and
cobbler don't seem to have
much to do with each other.
So many, many, many
trades like this, I know
before they used to
be blacksmiths, right?
So many types of trades
and of course, if you
have any other questions or doubts,
you can visit our website, englishpot.com.
We hope to see you guys there.
Bye.